Hello and welcome to this quick introduction to NRE labs
Have you tried getting started with automation, but felt like you had to spend months learning the terms and tools to even get started
Automation is a very powerful skill to have
but is a skill built over a long period of time across many different tools and processes
To help you get started with automation
we're announcing NRE labs
A way for you to quickly get started with automation without having to install anything on your laptop or know anything in advance
Everything is right here in the browser.
When people talk about automation, they tend to focus on managing configurations
While this is an important aspect automation, it's far from the complete picture
NRE labs was built by and for engineers
and as a result course content will also address real-world challenges like troubleshooting and
verification using automation
Let's take a look at our first lesson
Here we're presented with a terminal window where each network device or Linux machine is available for us to interact with, right here in the browser
These are not read-only devices. They're provisioned for you when you access this lesson and are yours to play with
To the left, we're presented with a lesson guide that explains the lesson content
As well as code or command snippets for us to execute in the terminal tabs on the right
If you've heard about REST APIs
But never had the time to set up an environment where you can play with them, have no fear
The lesson guide comes with buttons that you could click to type the right commands into the terminal so that you can quickly get started
However, you don't have to stick with the lab guide. The environment is yours
so when you're finished with the guided experience, have some fun with it
If you already have a little bit of experience with automation. We have lessons for you as well
Here's a more advanced example where we execute a set of tests using Jsnappy to ensure our BGP
configuration as well as our active peers is behaving the way that we expect
This is just an example though. You can create your own tests right here in the browser
NRE labs can also embed more advanced web content like Jupyter notebooks
These are very handy for running Python code in a GUI and there's a lot of existing automation education content that uses this format
So we want to make sure NRE labs has a home for these and more
NRE labs is just one runtime of the open source project Antidote
Antidote is an umbrella project that contains all the software that makes NRE labs possible including the lesson definitions
If you have a really good idea for a lesson that you want to make available in the browser
Stop by the github repo and consider opening a pull request. We would love to have you
Thank you